MARIÑO CARRANZA

PROFILE

I am a front-end developer born and raised in Guatemala, where at around 8 years old I started participating in my family's print shop. I grew up learning the trade, but most importantly I learned about learning. I learned that everything can be learned.

I improve every team I am a part of. I am used to working not only under pressure but to meet deadlines. My attention to detail has been pointed out to me by my supervisors and colleagues alike.

I am trusted to with finishing my projects correctly and on time, and I have also been untrusted to support new recruits in my department (answering their questions, showing them the most efficient way to accomplish a task, guiding them until they can teach others).

I am looking forward to a new challenge, and an opportunity to contribute and keep learning in a fulfilling field.

My sense of humor, team oriented mentality, and good communication skills are some of the skills I am going to be relying on to make a successful transition into the web development world. I want to keep learning in an environment that meets the same expectations I have for myself, and I am excited for the opportunity to translate my skills into the world of web development. I want to be a part of a team that builds better web experiences for the user.

EXPERIENCE

PREPRESS TECHNICIAN, DCG ONE; SEATTLE, WA 2014 – 2018-PRESENT Examine and manipulate art provided by graphic designers to ensure the final product will be the best it can be, re-touching images, creating layouts, plan ahead for processes needed after printing; interdepartmental communication to resolve potential problems before product hits production.

SMALL PRESS OPERATOR, DCG ONE; SEATTLE, WA – 2009 - 2014 - Conventional offset printing, maintenance of equipment, working with customer when press checks were required.

DIGITAL PREPRESS / PRESS OPERATOR, DIG ONE; SEATTLE, WA – 2006 - 2009 Examine and manipulate art provided by graphic designers to ensure the final product will be the best it can be, re-touching images, plan ahead for processes needed after printing.

EDUCATION

UW PROFESSIONAL & CONTINUING EDUCATION - FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER - JUN 2019 - DECEMBER 2019

CODE FELLOWS - 201: FOUNDATIONS OF SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT - JAN 2019

UNIVERSIDAD MARIANO GALVEZ – BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION, NO DEGREE 1997 -1999

SKILLS

fluent in Spanish, proficient in Javascript, HTML, CSS, jQuery, Creative Suite software (InDesign, Illustrator, Photoshop, XD), Pitstop, xmf, metrix.